Exercise 1-24, Application of Stress. Now, read each sentence of the paragraph after
the speaker. Use your rubber band, give a clear pitch change to the marked words,
and think about the meaning that the pitch is conveying. Hello. My name is Anne. I'm
taking American accent training. There's a lot to learn. But, I hope to make it as
enjoyable as possible. I should pick up on the American intonation pattern pretty
easily, although the only way to get it is to practice all the time.
I use the up and down or peaks and valleys intonation more than I used to. I've been
paying attention to pitch too.
It's like walking down a staircase. I've been talking to a lot of Americans lately
and they tell me that I'm easier to understand.
Anyway, I could go on and on, but the important thing is to listen well and
sound good. Well, what do you think? Do I? Listen and make any corrections. After
you've put in the accent marks where you think they belong, take a highlighter, and
as I read very slowly, mark the words that I stress. I'm going to exaggerate the
words far more than you'd normally hear in a normal reading of the paragraph. You can
mark either the whole word or just the strong syllable, whichever you prefer, so
that you have a bright spot of color for where the stress should fall. Note, if you
do the exercise only in pencil, your eye and mind will tend to skip over the accent
marks. The spots of color, however, will register as different and thereby
encourage your pitch change. This may strike you as unusual, but trust me, it
works. Practice reading the paragraph out loud three times on your own.